+65 93731871 jeffreydavid255@gmail.com github.com/Jeffrey-David linkedin.com/in/jeffrey-david-25a54a204 Portfolio: jeffrey-david.github.io

ABOUT

Enthusiastic engineering graduate with a B.Tech in Computer Science from VIT, Vellore, bringing a solid foundation in technology and a proactive approach to problem-solving. Experienced in applying technical skills and industry knowledge gained at Accenture. Currently pursuing a Master's in Information Systems at NTU, with a commitment to continuous learning in order to keep up with the technological advancements.

EXPERIENCE

Accenture Solutions Private Limited

Bangalore, India

Advanced Application Engineering Analyst

2022/11 - 2023/08

- Trained in Apache Hadoop File System and learned to use different big data analytics tools like Apache Hive, Spark, Cassandra and more as a fresher.
- Designed, developed, and implemented end-to-end data pipelines using Hadoop ecosystem tools such as HDFS, Map-Reduce, Hive, and Pig.
- Successfully integrated data from various sources including structured and unstructured data, enabling efficient processing and analysis within the Hadoop cluster.
- Implemented ETL (Extract, Transform, Load) processes to move data from various sources to the data warehouse
- Implemented real-time data processing solutions using tools like Apache Kafka.
- Documented processes, procedures, and best practices for Hadoop cluster management and data processing.

INTERNSHIPS

TalentKraft Pte Ltd Singapore

AI Project Development Intern

2024/01 - Present

- Conduct research and data gathering on relevant data for goal setting and performance review.
- Design and Develop Gen AI based solution to assist organisations in their Goal Setting and 360 Performance Review Process

The Sparks Foundation

Vellore, India

Graduate Rotational Internship Program (Remote)

2021/02 - 2021/03

- Conducted thorough data analysis to identify patterns, trends, and anomalies in diverse datasets.
- Evaluated the performance of machine learning models using appropriate metrics and fine-tuned algorithms for optimal results.
- Implemented data preprocessing techniques to clean, normalize and transform raw data into suitable formats for machine learning models.

EDUCATION

Nanyang Technological University

Singapore

Master of Science in Information Systems

B. Tech Computer Science and Engineering

2023/08 - Present

- CGPA: 4.80 / 5.00
- Completing in May, 2024
- Focusing on Data Science and Text Mining through my choice of coursework specialization.
- Courses: Text and Web Mining, Data Mining, Internet Programming, Research Methods for Data Analysis, Information Retrieval and Information Visualization

Vellore Institute of Technology

Vellore, India

2018/06 - 2022/05

• CGPA: 8.78 / 10.00

- Core Courses: Data Structures and Algorithms, Operating Systems, Database Management Systems, Computer Architecture
- Elective Courses: Web Mining, Statistical Data Analytics and Artificial Intelligence for Beginners

SKILLS

- Programming Python, Java, C, JavaScript
- Big Data Analytics Apache Hive, Apache Spark, Apache Hadoop
- Data Mining Machine Learning, Neural Networks, Natural Language Processing
- Data Visualization Tableau, D3.js
- Web Development HTML, CSS, Java Servlet, JSP, MySQL, AWS Deployment
- Soft Skills Self-Motivated, Detail-Oriented, Problem-Solving

PROJECTS

Aspect-Based Sentiment Analysis of LGBTQ Issues in Singapore

Text Mining, Deep Learning, NLP, Tableau

2024/01 - Present

- Web Scrap data from online discussion platforms like Reddit and HardwareZone.
- Train and Evaluate a BERT based Transformer Model for Sentiment and Aspect Classification
- Analyze the Aspect based Sentiments with respect to Time using Visualizations in order to gain insights.

Twitter Sentiment Analysis with MLP, CNN and BERT

Text Mining, Deep Learning, NLP

2023/08 - 2023/11

- Developed a machine learning model using Multilayer Perceptron (MLP), Convolutional Neural Network (CNN) and BERT for Twitter Sentiment Analysis.
- Implemented data preprocessing, model training and evaluation.
- Collaborated with team members to optimize model performance and accuracy.

Singapore COVID-19 StoryBoard

Data Visualization, Tableau

2023/08 - 2023/11

- Developed a comprehensive COVID-19 StoryBoard focusing on the situation in Singapore.
- Utilized Tableau for creating insightful data visualizations and interactive dashboards.
- Collected and analyzed relevant data for the StoryBoard.

Elegancy Stay - Hotel Management System

Web Development, AWS Deployment

2023/08 - 2023/11

- Developed a comprehensive Hotel Management System called "Elegancy Stay."
- Implemented features such as reservation management, room allocation and billing.
- Collaborated with a team to ensure the successful completion of the project.

Deep Learning Model for Analyzing Water Quality, Level, and Flow of Cauvery River

Deep Learning, Environmental Analysis

2021/11 - 2022/05

- Developed a Deep Learning model to analyze water quality, level and flow of the Cauvery River in India.
- Implemented features to predict and monitor environmental parameters.
- Contributed to the understanding and assessment of water resources using advanced technology.

CERTIFICATIONS

Certificate of Completion of Accenture Greenfield Training Program	2023/01 - 2022/11
• Intro to TensorFlow for Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, and Deep Learning	2021/03 - 2021/04
Artificial Intelligence for Beginners	2020/04 - 2020/05
Machine Learning Using Python	2020/04 - 2020/05
Statistical Data Analytics for Business Research	2020/04 - 2020/05
Data Science for Engineers - NPTEL	2021/01 – 2021/03
Programming in Java	2016/05 – 2016/06